<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Home</title><link>https://quanghieu31.github.io/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:44:17 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quanghieu31.github.io/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hà Nội</title><link>https://quanghieu31.github.io/thoughts/hanoi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:44:17 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanghieu31.github.io/thoughts/hanoi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://quanghieu31.github.io/hanoi/ho-guom.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I have never stayed in Hà Nội for more than a week over the past 3 years. And before that 3 years, I think I took Hà Nội for so much granted that I barely thought much about it. I guess only when you are not having something do you realize how much you miss it. For me, one of the things is places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been travelling heavily since 2018. There were a few places that really got me teary when I was about to leave&amp;ndash; Chicago, San Francisco, Carlisle, and of course, my home, Hà Nội.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First few words</title><link>https://quanghieu31.github.io/thoughts/first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 23:44:17 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanghieu31.github.io/thoughts/first/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is for Hieu in the future. Very nice working on your first web! After many weekend hours, you did it. It was thrilling learning experience. I am proud of you, please don&amp;rsquo;t be skeptical of yourself, even though I bet that you are right now haha. Anyhow, if you feel so, remember that everything is going to be daijoubu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to my bro (&lt;a href="https://cryptsu.github.io/"&gt;https://cryptsu.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;
) who has helped me so much during the design and development. My web structure was a mess as I had zero basic knowledge and only picked up new things along the way. He patiently taught me all the essential concepts and practices and helped me go through each of my HTML layout files and fix my errors that had taken me 1 month to find without success :D. Also, grateful for anh Hieu Phay (&lt;a href="https://hieuphay.com/en/"&gt;https://hieuphay.com/en/&lt;/a&gt;
), his guide showed me the rules and practices for building a good and effective website. I used to work with him in such a short time but his thinking and work ethics are still a significant part of my life compass.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>